Finding aid to the Academic Departments records CA.MS.01010
Smith College Archives
Academic Departments records
1880-2014
Smith College Archives
Smith College.
CA.MS.01010
36.833 linear feet (79 containers)
The collection contains papers of academic departments, including Interdepartmental, Sciences, Languages, and Social Sciences. The collection has publications, syllabuses, source notes, department records and memos, photographs, and material on departmental clubs.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation. Faculty tenure and promotion files, as well as inactive faculty files are closed permanently. Student academic records, student disciplinary records, and all records containing FERPA-covered student information are closed during the lifetime of the student. Student records created 100 years or more ago are assumed to be about deceased students. In all cases, the College Archives will continue to provide public access to materials that were intended to be public at the time of their creation (press releases, publications, etc.)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown.
Other Finding Aids
Many of the accessions have container lists that are available upon request by contacting specialcollections@smith.edu
Scope and Contents
The Academic Departments records contains material such as publications, syllabuses, source notes, department records and memos, photographs, and material on departmental clubs.
Smith College--Faculty,; Women's Studies Program; Women and Financial Independence Program; Department of Dance; Department of Theatre; Department of Sociology; Department of Social Sciences; Smith College. Department of Physics.; Department of Geology; Environmental Science and Policy Program; Department of Chemistry; Smith College. Department of Philosophy.; Smith College. Department of Religion and Biblical Literature; Department of Italian Language and Literature; The Jewish Studies Program; Department of Education and Child Study; Department of Art; Department of Classical Languages and Literatures
- Art: General, clubs, photographs (Box 1139)
- Art: Courses (Box 1140)
- Art: Student lecture notes -- Charlotte Baum (Class of 1915) and Catherine B. Hooper (Class of 1911) (Box 1141)
- Art: Slide collection accession book, 1920-1929 (Box 1141.1)
- Chemistry: A-E (Box 1245)
- Chemistry: F-Z (Box 1246)
- Chemistry: Clubs and Colloquiums (Box 1247)
- Chemistry: Minutes, 1919-1948 (Box 1248)
- Chemistry: Minutes, 1948-1977 (Box 1249)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted.
- Chemistry: Minutes, 1977-1981 (Box 1250)
- Chemistry: Administrative files, 1981-2003; Accession 2007-A-0062 (Box 1250.1, Box 1250.2)
- Classical Languages and Literatures: Greek (Box 1142)
- Classical Languages and Literatures: Latin (Box 1143)
- Classical Languages and Literatures: Publications (Box 1143.1)
- Education and Child Study: Courses and history (Box 1146)
- Education and Child Study: Teacher education (Box 1146.1)
- Education and Child Study: Smith College Day School (Box 1147)
- Education and Child Study: Smith College Campus School (Box 1147)
- Education and Child Study: Ellis M. Morgan Nursery School (Box 1147.1)
- Education and Child Study: Child Care Center (Box 1147.1)
- Education and Child Study: Infant Development Center (Box 1147.1)
- Education and Child Study: Smith-Northampton Summer School (Box 1147.1, Box 1147.2)
- Environmental Science (Box 1250.3)
- Environmental Studies: ENV 201/202 Environmental Integration II coursework interviews, 2014 (Box 1250.4)
- Geology (Box 1251)
- Hygiene and Bacteriology (Box 1252)
- Interdepartmental (General Literature, Jewish Studies, Pre-medical) (Box 1166)
- Italian (Box 1166)
- Microbiology (Box 1252)
- Philosophy (Box 1207)
  Some restricted materials.
- Physical Education: A-Z (Box 1208)
- Physical Education: Publications, 1920-1993 (Box 1209)
- Physical Education: Publications, 1994-2003 (Box 1209.1)
- Physical Education: General and hsitory (Box 1210)
- Physical Education: "Preparations for Drill," etc. (Box 1211)
- Physical Education: Instructions to instructors (Box 1211)
- Physical Education: Physical examinations - Sargent record book, 1896-1902 (Box 1212)
- Physical Education: Photographs (Box 1213)
- Physical Education: Class cards, 1959-1960 (Box 1214)
  Restricted
- Physical Education: Class cards, 1929-1959 (Box 1215)
- Physical Education: Class cards, 1959-1961 (Box 1216)
- Physical Education: Class cards, 1960-1963 (Box 1217)
- Physical Education (Box 1218)
- Physical Education: Scrapbook, 1913-1930 (Box 1218.1)
- Physical Education: Scrapbook, 1930-1935 (Box 1218.2)
- Physical Education: Scrapbook, 1935-1940 (Box 1218.3)
- Physical Education: Scrapbook, 1940-1945 (Box 1218.4)
- Physical Education: Scrapbook, 1945-1949 (Box 1218.5)
- Physical Education: Scrapbook, 1949-1956 (Box 1218.6)
- Physical Education: Scrapbook, 1956-1962 (Box 1218.7)
- Physical Education: Scrapbook, 1962-1969 (Box 1218.8)
- Physics (Box 1253)
- Physics: Composite photographs, 1880s (Box 1254)
- Religion: Early text book sheets (Box 1219)
- Religion: A-C (Box 1220)
- Religion: D-Z (Box 1220.1)
- Sciences: General (Box 1222)
- Sociology and Social Science (Box 1266)
- Sociology and Social Science: Jahnige Social Science Research Center (Box 1267)
- Speech: A-D (Box 1269)
- Speech: E-Sh (Box 1270)
- Speech: St-Z (Box 1271)
- Speech: Intercollegiate Poetry Reading Festival (Box 1272)
- Theater and Speech: A-P (Box 1273)
- Theater and Speech: Q-Z (Box 1273.1)
- Theatre: Syllabi, 1949-1975 (Box 1274)
- Theatre: Syllabi, 1976-1977 (Box 1275)
- Theatre: Visiting dramatic and dance groups (Box 1276)
- Theatre: Dance groups (Box 1277)
- Theatre: Dance, 1913-1936 (Box 1277)
- Theatre: Dance, 1936-1953 (Box 1278)
- Theatre: Dance, 1953-2000s (Box 1279)
- Theatre: Dance group scrapbook, 1926-1949 (Box 1276.1)
- Theatre: Dance group scrapbook, 1949-1961 (Box 1276.2)
- Zoology: A-Courses (Box 1256)
- Zoology: Courses-Plans (Box 1257, Box 1257.1)
- Zoology: R-Z (Box 1257.2)
- Zoology: Biological Society (Box 1258)
- Zoology: Accession books (Box 1259)
- Zoology: Contributions 1-66 (Box 1260)
- Zoology: Contributions 67-128 (Box 1261)
- Zoology: Contributions 129-189 (Box 1262)
- Zoology: Contributions 190-255 (Box 1263)
- Zoology: Student lecture notes (Box 1264)